Hello everyone and welcome to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine
and today we have an
intermediate level lesson
about going to the bank.
That's right, today we're going to go to
the bank and we need to do something there.
We're not going to put money in the bank
actually. We're going to make a transfer.
Okay, so you'll learn all
about this in a minute.
Let's take a listen
to the dialogue first.
Good morning. Welcome to Bank of the USA.
How may I help you today?
Hi, I need to transfer some money
to another account. It's urgent.
Okay, have you made a wire
transfer at our bank before?
No, I've never made a transfer before.
It's all right. I will take
you through the procedure.
Are you transferring
funds to a company
or an individual account?
A company account. I need to pay a bill.
Okay, I'll need the name of the
company and their bank routing number.
As well as their banks
address and phone number.
I have all the information in this folder.
Well, you've come prepared.
I have all the necessary
materials so we can
go ahead and make
the transfer right now.
It's a simple transaction
and we can process it today.
Oh, that's such a relief. I didn't want the
payment to be overdue. Thank you so much.
It's my pleasure.
All right, we're back. So interesting
dialogue, very common situation.
We need to transfer
money to another account.
So we have some very
interesting vocab words right there.
Why don't we take a look at
those on language takeaway?
Language takeaway.
So Marco, the first
word is one that you've
already said a couple
of times in today's lesson.
It is to transfer.
Okay, that's right.
We need to transfer money.
So to transfer, what does this verb mean?
So to transfer means to move from
one place to another in the case of money,
you're moving money
from one bank to another
bank or from one
account to another account.
So just think of transferring as moving.
That's right, but the bank teller also
mentioned something about a wire transfer.
So that's basically the same thing, right?
That's right. So when
you're talking about
money, you don't actually
take a bag of money
and you don't walk to another
bank to put it in the account.
A wire transfer means that
the transfer is electronic.
One bank tells another bank that
you're going to exchange this money.
So it's going to move
from one person to another
person or from one
company to another company.
But it's never actually the money itself.
It's always just the number
of funds in the account.
That's right. Okay.
So a wired transfer to transfer money
electronically from one account to another.
And talking about this word account,
we're talking about a bank account.
What is this?
Well, this is really important, even
if you're not making a wire transfer.
Or if you're not working
at a bank, this is something
that most people have
for their personal use.
So an account is a space
for money in a bank that's
kind of registered to one
person or one company.
And there are many, many
different kinds of accounts.
That's right. Many of you
probably have a savings account.
This is where you keep your
money to save for the future.
Or many companies or people have a
checking account or a default account where
basically you put
money in, but you're also
taking money out and paying for
bills and paying to go to the movies, etc.
Yeah. So these different
accounts have different rules.
They have rules about how
much money you can keep
in them or how much money
you need to open them.
So the basic word
here is account.
And just remember that companies
and people can all have accounts at a bank.
That's right. Okay. So when
talking about an account,
we're talking about
transferring money to another
account, we don't say we want to transfer
money. We say we want to transfer funds.
Funds. So funds, we usually say in the
plural funds with an S, this means money.
So we're talking about transferring funds
from one company to another or I could say,
I need to deposit funds in my account.
That's right. Now, an
interesting word because
funds with an S at
the end, that's a plural
noun, as you said. But if we use it in the
singular, it could also be a verb to fund.
That's right. And that means to
pay for something or someone.
And so my grandfather
funded my college education.
He paid money for
my college education.
That's right. Okay. So both words either
the verb or the noun have to do with money.
And when we're talking
about transferring
money, we're talking about
different, a type of transaction.
Right. We're at a bank transfer or a
wire transfer is a type of transaction.
That's right. So a
transaction is a noun.
And it's something that
you do at a bank, for example,
usually involving the exchange of money. So
a wire transfer is a kind of transaction,
but also depositing or
putting money into my
savings account is also
a kind of transaction.
That's right. So a
transaction is kind of like a
business move or a business
deal involving money.
For example, a transaction
can also be buying a car.
That's right. So
the transaction is,
I give my money to Marco
the car salesperson and the
transaction is exchanging
that money for the car.
That's right. Okay. And
lastly, since we needed
to pay a bill, we were
worried that the bill
will be overdue. And that's why we
really needed to make this wire transfer.
Okay. So to be
overdue is to be late.
So think about do. This is the time
when something has to be done by.
So for example, if the bill for the
electricity is due on Wednesday, but I pay it
on Thursday, it's overdue.
Okay. So it not only
has to do with money, it could
also be something that is late.
For example, if I visit my grandma
after not going there for three months,
you would say this
visit is long overdue.
That means Marco should
have visited his grandmother
earlier, but he didn't.
That's right. Okay.
So a lot of great vocab.
They're all involving
banks and the different
types of words you may
find when transferring
funds. So why don't we
listen to the dialogue
again and we'll be back
in a bit with Fluency
Building. Good morning.
Welcome to Bank of the USA.
How may I help you today?
Hi, I need to transfer some
money to another account.
It's urgent. Okay.
Have you made a wire
transfer at our bank
before? No, I've never made
a transfer before. It's
all right. I will take you
through the procedure.
Are you transferring funds
to a company or an
individual account?
A company account. I
need to pay a bill. Okay.
I'll need the name of the
company and their bank routing
number, as well as their
bank's address and phone
number. I have all the
information in this folder.
Well, you've come
prepared. I have all the
necessary materials so
we can go ahead and make
the transfer right now.
It's a simple transaction
and we can process it
today. Oh, that's such a relief.
I didn't want the
payment to be overdue.
Thank you so much.
It's my pleasure. All right.
We're back. So we have
three key phrases for you.
Let's take a look at those
now on Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder. So
our first phrase comes
from something that the
person at the bank told
the client that person
said it's all right.
I will take you through the procedure.
Okay, so let's look at this word procedure.
Procedure can be many
different things, but what
is it in this case? It's
basically the steps
or the process of taking money from the
account and transferring it to another one.
That's the procedure. What
we have to do, all the steps, you
have to fill out the
paperwork, you have to sign
here and all these things.
Right. So we're talking
about a wire transfer.
So there is a procedure
for doing a wire transfer.
That means, like you
say, there are steps that
we have to go through
to complete this action,
but we can also have a
medical procedure. So a
heart surgery has its own
procedure, but that's
that's very different
from a wire transfer
procedure, but it still has
different steps and
different things that you must
do in order to operate.
But when we have a bank
teller who will take us
through the procedure,
this means that he or
she will help us understand
the steps we need to
complete. That's right.
So this we could also use
is in another bank scenario,
if maybe my little brother
wants to open a bank account.
So I'm going to take him through the
procedure of what he needs. He needs to maybe
get a copy of his ID. He
needs to have $20, etc.
Take him through the procedure. So you're
going to help him. All right. That's right.
And after this, we find out why the person
is so anxious to transfer this money.
The person says, I have
a company account.
I need to pay a bill. So
this is why the money
is going to be transferred
from one place to another
to pay the bill. So this
is something we say,
not just about, you
know, company things or
business things, we say
about our things at home,
like the electricity
bill. That's right.
And actually, this is
more and more common.
We pay our bills using our
electronic banking services.
So for example, maybe he
needs to pay the electricity
bill or the telephone
bill. And this is why
we're transferring
money. So to pay a bill is to
cancel the bill. That's
right. So I could say, it's
time to pay the bills.
It's the end of the month,
or, oh, shoot, I forgot
to pay the bills again.
They're going to
turn my electricity off.
That's right. And now
an interesting phrase here,
very specific to making
transfers when we talk about
bank routing number,
a bank routing number.
Well, this is pretty simple
actually. If you're going to
transfer money, you
need to be able to tell the
bank where the money
will go. So you can't just say
Mr Smith, you have to have
a number for the account.
And each number
is unique. It's special.
And it's usually very,
very long. That's right.
And actually, it also has
to do with what bank it is,
because obviously, you
can't just say, oh, bank
of USA, because, you
know, maybe there are two
banks with the same name,
or maybe there's one bank
of USA in the United
States. And there's another
one in, I don't know,
in Europe. Right.
So each bank will have
a certain number or letter
combination in the
bank routing number.
And so the kind of account,
is it savings, or is it a business
account, and so on and
so forth, so that you know
exactly where the money
will go. Because you don't
want to give the money
to the wrong person.
That's right. Okay. So a lot
of great things on this lesson.
Why don't we listen to the
dialogue for one last time?
Good morning. Welcome to Bank of the USA.
How may I help you today?
Hi, I need to transfer some money
to another account. It's urgent.
Okay. Have you made a wire
transfer at our bank before?
No, I've never made a transfer before.
It's all right. I will take
you through the procedure.
Are you transferring
funds to a company,
or an individual account?
A company account. I need to pay a bill.
Okay. I'll need the name
of the company and their
bank routing number,
as well as their bank's
address and phone number.
I have all the information in this folder.
Well, you've come prepared.
I have all the necessary
materials, so we
can go ahead and make
the transfer right now.
It's a simple transaction,
and we can process it today.
Oh, that's such a relief. I didn't want the
payment to be overdue. Thank you so much.
It's my pleasure.
So Marco, this is really,
really important stuff,
even if you're not
talking about the business
context, but you're trying to make
transactions for your personal life.
That's right. Just imagine
maybe you're abroad,
you're in the United States, and maybe
your parents need to send you money.
So maybe you need to go to
the bank and receive those funds.
So now you have the language
and the vocab necessary
to more or less talk
about a bank transfer.
You can say I was wired
money from Spain, for example.
Right. And one of the
most famous places to do
this that you'll find all
over the United States
is Western Union. That's
right. You can just go
up to them and say I
need to transfer money or I
need to transfer funds.
And so they will send the
money from one Western
Union to another Western Union.
And then the person
at home or wherever
will pick up your money. And so they will
wire the money from one place to another.
That's right. And I think
this is how it started.
The wired transferring
was, I don't think it was
originally with banks. I
think it was something
of some sort of service similar to
Western Union or maybe Western Union.
Yeah. And it was like telegraphs?
Yeah, something like
this. But I don't know if it
was from bank to bank. It's
an interesting story, though.
Well, have to look it
up and let you know.
I'm not sure of
the story either.
But if you're out there and you need to
wire some money now, you know how to do it.
Well, not how to do it, but
you have to talk about it.
We hope you have luck
with this. And if you have
any questions, you know
where to find us, EnglishPod.
com. All right. We'll
see you guys there. Bye.